Michalle Khan (she/her/hers)

917-969-2631 | michallekhan9@gmail.com | https://mkhan42.github.io/MK/ | https://mkhan42.github.io/MK/ | www.linkedin.com/in/michalle-khan | https://twitter.com/michalle_io

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

A full-stack software engineer with a background in computer science, software engineering, and customer success, who works well under pressure with a dedication to project success. Takes on challenges with focus and grit with strong problem-solving skills. Excited to continue to build knowledge and gain experience with your team on this journey.

SKILLS

C++ | Javascript | Python | Vanilla Javascript | Arduino | HTML5 | CSS Express.js | Node.js | Django | React | BootStrap | EJS | Liquid.js | Jinga2 MySQL | SQL | Postgres | MongoDB | Mongoose Git. | GitHub | Linux/Unix | WEKA | Heroku | MailChimp | Postman Adobe XD | InDesign | Photoshop | Lightroom | Illustrator | Figma | Procreate

SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT PROJECTS

Cat-Fish | https://mkhan42.github.io/Cat-Fish/ | https://github.com/mkhan42/Cat-Fish

- A web-based game, in which the user is playing as a cat who has to catch all the fish on the screen. The user must do so while avoiding all the fruits and vegetables falling from the top of the screen.
- Built with Vanilla Javascript, DOM Manipulation, CSS, HTML, and Canvas. Deployed on GitHub.

Artstagram | https://artstagrams.herokuapp.com | https://github.com/mkhan42/Artstagram

- A social media platform for artists to share their work and collaborate with other artists.
- Built with Express.js, Liquid.js, Mongoose, MongoDB, CSS, HTML, and BootStrap. Deployed on Heroku.

Find-Furry-Friends | https://find-furry-friends-mern.herokuapp.com/ |

- A platform to post about lost or found pets. Other people can comment to update about any information.
- Built with Express.js, React.js, Mongoose, MongoDB, CSS, HTML, and BootStrap. Deployed on Heroku.

RezKeeper | https://frontend-rezkeeper.vercel.app/ | https://github.com/mkhan42/rezkeep

- A personal keeper app to keep track of all the restaurants a user plans to go to and has been to.
- Built with Python, Django, React.js, JavaScript, CSS, HTML, and BootStrap. Deployed on Vercel and Heroku.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Technical Specialist | Apple | New York, NY

07/2021 - 05/2022

- Offered technical support and solutions to 20+ customers per day on how to resolve issues with their devices.
- Repaired devices by troubleshooting, asking relevant questions, and running various tests and diagnostics.
- Gained sales support knowledge and made up 5% of the sales within 3 months.

Financial Aid Representative | Fordham University | New York, NY

08/2017 - 12/2020

• Advised current, prospective, and graduate students through the financial aid process.

UX/UI Design Intern | CariClub | New York, NY

08/2019 - 12/2019

- Leveraged HTML, CSS, and JavaScript to produce email marketing campaigns.
- Designed and revamped company One Pagers and PowerPoints using Figma and company style guide.
- Collaborated with the marketing team to design and plan social media posts.

EDUCATION

Software Engineering Immersive | General Assembly

May 2022 - August 2022

Fordham University

August 2017 - February 2021

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science, Minor in New Media and Digital Design Institutional Honors cum laude. GPA 3.6

FordhamHacks Organizer

Courses

Computer Science I & II | Computer Algorithms | Computer Organization | Discrete Structures I & II | Data Structures | Database Systems | Data Mining | Data Communications and Networks | Information and Retrieval Systems | Information and Web Programming | Internet and Web Programming | Operating Systems | Theory of Computation